A Scream in the Night is a thriller, crime, mystery
film directed by Fred C. Newmeyer.
A colonial police detective in an Eastern seaport seeks a stolen gem, and
infiltrates the underworld by posing as a look-alike wharfside bar owner.
Jack Wilson / Butch Curtain, played by Lon Chaney Jr..
Joe Bentley, played by John Ince.
Mora, played by Zarah Tazil.
Johnny Fly, played by Manuel López.
Inspector Green (as Dick Cramer), played by Richard Cramer.
Edith Bentley, played by Sheila Terry.
The Scream is an art composition created by
Norwegian artist Edvard Munch in 1893.
The Norwegian name of the piece is Skrik ('Scream'), and the German title under which it
was first exhibited is Der Schrei der Natur ('The Scream of Nature').
The agonized face in the painting has become one of the most iconic images in art, seen as
representing a profound experience of existential dread related to the human condition.
Munch's work, including The Scream, had a formative
influence on the Expressionist movement.
Munch recalled that he had been out for a walk at sunset when suddenly
the setting sun's light turned the clouds "a blood red".
He sensed an "infinite scream passing through nature".
Scholars have located the spot along a fjord path overlooking Oslo and have suggested various explanations for the unnaturally orange sky, ranging
from the effects of a volcanic eruption to a psychological reaction by Munch to his sister's commitment at a nearby lunatic asylum.
Munch created two versions in paint and two in pastels, as well as a
lithograph stone from which several prints survive.
Both painted versions have been stolen from public museums, but since recovered.
In 2012, one of the pastel versions commanded the highest nominal price
paid for an artwork at a public auction at that time.
The film explores themes of police, detective, parrot, knife throwing.
The tone is mind_bending and intense.